<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

<string name="establishment"><![CDATA[
    <html>
    <body style="text-align:justify;color:black;">
    <p>Bangladesh Academy for Rural Development(BARD) started its journey as a training institute on
        27th May 1959
        under the dynamic leadership of famous rural development architect Dr. Akhter Hameed Khan to
        train different
        stakeholders of Village Agricultural and Industrial Development (V-AID) programme. Since
        then, BARD is
        an internationally reputed training institute of the country. In course of time, research
        and action
        research were included as its regular activities. BARD has incorporated the findings of
        research and action
        research in training curriculum in order to make it more pragmatic. This unified approach of
        training,
        research and action research of the Academy to solve problems of rural areas has given
        special significance
        to rural development of the country. This approach has been following meticulously with a
        view to making
        its training practical, field-oriented, effective and meaningful. Through its diversified
        training
        programmes, the Academy has made significant contributions to the human resources
        development specially for
        rural level planning and management of rural development programs as well as projects
        throughout the country.
        BARD has also been contributing to develop human resources outside the country through
        sharing regional and
        international perspective and experiences of rural development in a limited way.</p>

    <p> The academy has formed a
        congenial training environment for the officials of government organizations (Gos) and non
        -government (NGOs),
        representatives of local government, co-operative institutions, students and researchers of
        universities
        and other institutions for higher learning. With the assistance of UNDP, FAO, WFP, ILO,
        CIRDAP, SAARC, AARDO,
        KOIKA, JICA and COMSEC, BARD also conducts seminars, workshops and training programs on
        various issues of
        rural development for the participants of the countries in the Asia-Pacific and Africa
        regions. The training
        calender displays the schedules for selected training activities of the Academy during
        2015-16 though there
        is scope of accommodating other training programs through discussions with the
        sponsoring/donor agencies and
        concerned individuals.</p>

    <p>The Academy is located at Kotbari under Comilla Sadar South Upazilla (sub district) at eight
        kilometers to
        the west of Comilla city. Comilla is connected with Dhaka (100 kilometers) and Chittagong
        (170 kilometers)
        by railway and road transport. The Academy\'s campus has an area of 156 acres of plain and
        hilly lands of
        Lalmai hills with orchards, nursries, parks, vegetable farms, fruit and flower gardens. The
        campus is almost
        self-contained. It has two auditoriums, four conference halls, five class rooms, three
        cafeterias, one health clinic,
        one sports and recreation center, telephone exchange, post office, bank, mosque, consumer
        store, laundry,
        haircutting saloon, a development communication unit with modern equipments, one computer
        lab, a modern libray
        with internet facilities having more than 65 thousands latest collection of books, journals
        and periodicals.
        The Academy has a liaison office at 2/GA/2, Nawab Habibullah Road, Shahbag, Dhaka,
        Bangladesh. Tel. 02-8627813.</p>

    <p>
        Address for Correspondence<br/>
        Director General<br/>
        BARD, Kotbari, Comilla, Bangladesh<br/>
        Phone : 081-63600 (Direct)<br/>
        PABX : 081-60601-6, Extn. 301(Off.), 401(Res.)<br/>
        Fax : 081-68406<br/>
        E-mail : dgbard1959@gmail.com; trainingbard@gmail.com<br/>
        Web : www.bard.gov.bd<br/>
    </p>
    </body>
    </html>
    ]]></string>

    <string name="functionsOftheAcademy"><![CDATA[
        <html>

        <body style="text-align:justify;">
        <p>
            1) Conduct research in rural development and allied
            fields.<br/>
            2) Conduct training of government officials and
            others concerned with rural development.<br/>
            3) Test and experiment concepts and theories of
            development.<br/>
            4) Evaluate the programs and activities relating
            to rural development.<br/>
            5) Provide advisory and consultative service to
            the government and other agencies.<br/>
            6) Guide and supervise national and foreign students
            in their dissertation works.<br/>
            7) Conduct national and international seminars,
            conferences and workshops.<br/>
            8) Help policy planners in the field of Rural
            development.
        </p>
        </body>
        </html>
        ]]></string>

    <string name="research"><![CDATA[
        <html>

        <body style="text-align:justify;">
        <p>
            The academy has been conducting socio-economic research
            since its inception. Research findings are used as training
            materials and inputs for initiating action research by the
            academy itself, and as information material and policy inputs
            by the Ministers, Planning commission and Policy Makers for
            undertaking development programs. In some particular cases,
            these are also disseminated among the international agencies
            and institutions.
        </p>
        </body>
        </html>
        ]]></string>

    <string name="training"><![CDATA[
        <html>

        <body style="text-align:justify;">
        <p>
            The Academy is a designated national training institute.
            Its training clientele includes both officials and
            non-officials. Officials comprise civil servants,
            officers of nation building departments and international
            participants of development sector organizations while the
            non-officials are local councilors , local leaders, members
            of co-operatives. Students of educational institutions and
            members of voluntary organizations. Besides, a large number
            of international clientele including students, scholars,
            consultants, governments officials, members of diplomatic
            corps and international agencies visit the Academy.
        </p>

        </body>
        </html>
        ]]></string>

    <string name="actionResearch"><![CDATA[
        <html>

        <body style="text-align:justify;">
        <p>
            BARD conducts experimental projects to evolve models of
            improved institutions, administrative structures,
            coordination and method of production. The project
            activities usually involve the villagers, development
            institutions, local councils and government officials.
            So far the academy has conducted about 50 experimental
            projects on various aspects of rural development. Through
            these pilot experimentations, it has been able to evolve
            the following rural development models that have already
            been replicated throughout the country as components of
            the Comilla Model:
        </p>

        <p>

            1)Two-tier Cooperatives.<br/>
            2)Thana (presently Upozila) Training and Development
            Centre (TTDC).<br/>
            3)Rural works program (RWP).<br/>
            4)Thana (presently Upozila) irrigation Program (TIP).<br/>
        </p>

        <p>
            Besides, government has been replicating two recent models
            of BARD which are: Comprehensive Village Development Program
            (CVDP) and Small Farmers Development Foundation (SFDF).</p>


        </body>
        </html>
        ]]></string>

<string name="facilitiesAtBard"><![CDATA[
    <html>

    <body style="text-align:justify;">
    A good deal of facilities has been developed at the campus to
    meet the needs of trainees, visitors and campus residents,
    There are seven hostels including one for ladies as well as
    various types of guest houses with a total capacity of 390 seats.
    Among these, five hostels are equipped with hot water system. For
    organizing training, workshops, seminars, symposiums and conferences.
    There are five AC classrooms, four AC conference halls, IT Lab, Two
    AC auditoriums and a library with about 65000 titles of books. There
    are bank, a post office, a cooperative store, a medical centre and a
    sports complex with a variety of sports facilities. Adequate residential
    quarters have been built for the faculty and other employees.
    </body>
    </html>
    ]]></string>

    <string name="contactInformation"><![CDATA[<html>

<body style="text-align:justify;">
<p><img src="file:///android_asset/dg_sir.jpg" width="150px;" height="180px;"><br/>
    <b>Director General</b><br/>
    Salahuddin Mahmud<br/>
    Bangladesh Academy for rural Development (BARD)<br/>
    Kotbari, Comilla-3503, Bangladesh<br/>
    Telephone : (081)60601-6<br/>
    Fax : (081)68406<br/>
    e-mail : dgbard1959@gmail.com<br/>
    <t>: bardbd@yahoo.com<br/></t>
    Website : www.bard.gov.bd
</p>
<p><img src="file:///android_asset/mirkasem.jpg" width="150px;" height="180px;"><br/>
    <b>Additional Director General</b><br/>
    Mohammed Mir Kashem<br/>
    mkashem_bard@yahoo.com
</p>

<p>
    <img src="file:///android_asset/sharifullah.jpg" width="150px;" height="180px;"
         style="border:2px;"><br/>
    <b>Director(Project)</b><br/>
    Dr. A.K. Sharifullah<br/>
    Ph.D. in Agricultural Engineering (Major in Land and Water Resources Engineering), UPLB,
    Los
    Banos, The Phillipines<br/>
    M.Sc. Irrigation Engineering, CIT, U.K.<br/>
    B.Sc. In Agricultural Engineering, BAU, Mymensingh<br/>
    Certificate Course (International Training Methodology),<br/>
    INTAN, Malaysia<br/>
    Field of Specialization: Local Level Planning, Project Management, Training Methodology,
    Research Methodology, Financial Management<br/>
    Email:bardresearch@gmail.com

</p>

<p><img src="file:///android_asset/anwar.jpg" width="150px;" height="180px;"><br/>
    <b>Director (Research)</b><br/>
    Dr. S. J. ANWAR ZAHID<br/>
    B.Com (Hons.)<br/>
    Rajshahi University<br/>
    bardresearch@gmail.com

</p>

<p><img src="file:///android_asset/hamid.jpg" width="150px;" height="180px;"><br/>
    <b>Director (Rural Sociology & Demography)</b><br/>
    Dr. Md. Abdul Hamid<br/>
    Ph.D. (Natural Science and Technology), Okayama University, Japan<br/>
    M.Sc. (Agri. Structural Engineering), BAU, Mymensingh<br/>
    B.Sc. (Hons.) (Agricultural Engineering), BAU, Mymensingh<br/>
    International Course on Technologies for Rural Development and integration them into Rural
    Development Schemes, NIRD, India<br/>
    International Course on Role of Modern Irrigation Techniques in improving Food Security,
    Jordan<br/>
    Field of Specialization: Rural Development, Research Methodology, Training, Environment,
    Irrigation and Water Resource Development, Geo-technical Engineering<br/>
    Email: drhamid_bard@yahoo.com<br/>
</p>

<p><img src="file:///android_asset/kamrul.jpg" width="150px;" height="180px;"><br/>
    <b>Director (Training)</b><br/>
    Dr. Kamrul Ahsan<br/>
    Ph.D. in Environmental Science, IES, Rajshahi University<br/>
    B.Sc. (Agricultural Engineering), BAU, Mymensingh<br/>
    Diploma (Agricultural Management in Rural Development Projects), NAC, Denmark
    Certificate Course (Agrarian Reforms and Rural Development), Taiwan<br/>
    Certificate Course (Rural Development with Special Emphasis on Korean Experience), Korea<br/>
    Workshop on Agricultural Insurance on Sustainabile Family Farming, Malaysia<br/>
    Field of Specialization: Environmental and Agriculture Development, Irrigation Management
    and Project Management<br/>
    Email: kamrul_61@yahoo.com<br/></p>

<p><img src="file:///android_asset/swapan.jpg" width="150px;" height="180px;"><br/>
    <b>Director (Rural Economics & Management)</b><br/>
    Dr. Swapan Kumar Dasgupta<br/>
    Ph.D. (Managerial Economics), Tottori University, Japan<br/>
    M.Sc. (Econ),(Food Policy and Commodity Trade) University of Wales, Swansea, U.K.<br/>
    M.A. (Economics), Chittagong University<br/>
    B.A.(Hons.)(Economics ), Chittagong University<br/>
    Diploma (Agricultural Management in Rural Development Projects), NAC, Denmark<br/>
    Field of Specialization: Rural Economics, Food Security and Union Level Co-ordination<br/>
    Email: swpndsgpt687@gmail.com<br/>
</p>

<p><img src="file:///android_asset/masudul.jpg" width="150px;" height="180px;"><br/>
    <b>Director (Rural Education)</b><br/>
    Dr. Masudul Hoq Chowdhury<br/>
    Post Doctorate (Education for Sustainable Development), United
    Nations University, Institute of Advanced Studies, Tokyo, Japan<br/>
    Ph.D., Fisheries Extension, Hiroshima University, Japan<br/>
    M.S. Hiroshima University, Japan<br/>
    B.Sc. (Fisheries Hons), BAU, Mymensingh<br/>
    Certificate Course (Rural Development-Poultry), Wales, U.K.<br/>
    Diploma (Agricultural Management in Rural Development Projects), N.A.C. Denmark.<br/>
    Field of Specialization: Aquaculture Education for Sustainable Development Environmental ,
    Environmental Education and Ecological Sanitation<br/>
    Email: chowdhury62@yahoo.com<br/>
</p>

<p><img src="file:///android_asset/safikul2.jpg" width="150px;" height="180px;"><br/>
    <b>Director (Rural Administration & Local Govt.)</b><br/>
    Md. Shafiqul Islam<br/>
    M.A. (Mass Communication and Journalism) Dhaka University<br/>
    B.A. (Hons)(Mass Communication and Journalism) Dhaka University<br/>
    Field of Specialization: Development Communication<br/>
    Email:shafiqbd@fastmail.fm<br/></p>

<p><img src="file:///android_asset/mijanur.jpg" width="150px;" height="180px;"><br/>
    <b>Director (Administration)</b><br/>
    Md. Mizanur Rahman<br/>
    M.P.S. (Food and Nutrition Planning), UPLB, Philippines<br/>
    M.Sc. Agril. Economics (Agricultural Cooperation), BAU, Mymensingh<br/>
    B.Sc. (Hons.), Agril. Economics, BAU, Mymensingh<br/>
    Certificate Course in Regional Development Planning, UNCRD, Japan<br/>
    Filed of Specialization: Farm Management, Cooperative Management, Local Level Planning, Food
    and Nutrition Planning<br/>
    Email: mizanbard@yahoo.com<br/></p>


<p><img src="file:///android_asset/safikul.jpg" width="150px;" height="180px;"><br/>
    <b>Director In-charge (Agriculture & Environment)</b><br/>
    Dr. Md. Shafiqul Islam<br/>
    Ph.D. in Agricultural Extension and Rural Development,
    BSMRAU, Gazipur<br/>
    M.Sc. (Production Economics and Farm Management), BAU, Mymensingh<br/>
    B.Sc. (Hons.) Agril. Economics BAU, Mymensingh<br/>
    Field of Specialization: Agricultural Economics, Agricultural Extension and Sustainable
    Development<br/>
    Email: dshafiqul@gmail.com, islam_bard@yahoo.com<br/></p>

<p><img src="file:///android_asset/abulkalam.jpg" width="150px;" height="180px;"><br/>
    <b>Joint Director (Agriculture & Environment)</b><br/>
    Abul Kalam Azad<br/>
    M.S. in Rural Development Management, Khon Kaen
    University, Thiland<br/>
    B.Sc. In Agril. Engg.(Hons.), BAU, Mymensingh<br/>
    Certificate Course (Rural Development- Water and Irrigation Management), Wales, U.K.<br/>
    Certificate Course (Agricultural Machinery and Management), AIT, Thailand<br/>
    Certificate Course (Sustainable Agricultural Development),
    KRC, South Korea<br/>
    Certificate Course (Geo Informatics Application in RD), NIRD, India<br/>
    Field of Specialization: Irrigation and Water Management<br/>
    Email: kalamazad12@yahoo.com<br/></p>


<p>
    <img src="file:///android_asset/milankanti.jpg" width="150px;" height="180px;"><br/>
    <b>Joint Director (Rural Economics)</b><br/>
    Milan Kanti Bhattacharjee<br/>
    M.A. (English), Chittagong University and B.A. (Hons.)<br/>
    Certificate Course (Development Communication), Wales, U.K.<br/>
    Certificate Course (Management of National Resources for Sustainable Rural Livelihoods)
    NIRD, India<br/>
    Certificate Course (Participatory Project Cycle Management for Community Development), Fiji<br/>
    Field of Specialization: Development Communication, Participatory Rural Appraisal (PRA)<br/>
    Email: milankantibard@yahoo.com<br/></p>

<p><img src="file:///android_asset/abdul.jpg" width="150px;" height="180px;"><br/>
    <b>Joint Director (Rural Administration)</b><br/>
    Abdul Quader<br/>
    M.S.S. (Public Administration), Chittagong University and B.S.S.(Hons.)<br/>
    Certificate Course (Participatory Development), Wales, U.K.<br/>
    Diploma (Decentralized Planning for Rural Development),
    NIRD, India<br/>
    Field of Specialization: Local Government and Development Administration<br/>
    Email:quader.bard@gmail.com<br/></p>

<p><img src="file:///android_asset/abdulkarim.jpg" width="150px;" height="180px;"><br/>
    <b>Joint Director (General Administration)</b><br/>
    Abdul Karim<br/>
    MS (Comparative Study on Politics in Asia(CSPA), Faculty of Law, Kyushu University, Japan<br/>
    M.S.S. (Public Administration) and B.S.S.(Hons.), Chittagong University<br/>
    Post Graduate Diploma (Decentralized Plannin for Rural Development), NIRD, Hyderabad, India<br/>
    Field of Specialization:Local Government, Rural Development, Institution Building, Project
    Monitoring and Evaluation, Development Administration, Good Governance<br/>
    Email: bardkarim@yahoo.com<br/></p>

<p><img src="file:///android_asset/kamrul.jpg" width="150px;" height="180px;"><br/>
    <b>Joint Director (Rural Education)</b><br/>
    Dr. Md. Kamrul Hasan<br/>
    Ph.D. (Sociology), IBS, Rajshahi University<br/>
    M.S.S. (Sociology) and B.S.S. (Hons.) , Dhaka University<br/>
    Diploma (Managing Human Development Program for Rural Reconstruction), NIRD, Hyderabad,
    India.<br/>
    Field of Specialization: Rural Sociology and Development, Bangladesh Society and Culture and
    Human Development<br/>
    Email: hasan.kamrul17@yahoo.com<br/></p>

<p><img src="file:///android_asset/newaz.jpg" width="150px;" height="180px;"><br/>
    <b>Joint Director (Agriculture and Environment)</b><br/>
    Newaz Ahmed Chowdhury<br/>
    Master of Rural Development Management (MRDM), Khon Kaen University, Thailand<br/>
    B.Sc. (Hons.) in Forestry, Chittagong University<br/>
    Certificate Course (Management of Natural Resources for Sustainable Rural Livelihoods),
    NIRD, India<br/>
    Certificate Course (Development Evaluation), Ottawa, Canada<br/>
    Certificate Course (Renewable Energy), New Delhi, India<br/>
    Certificate Course (Participatory Methodology), Feldafing, Germany<br/>
    Field of Specialization: Forestry, Environment, Natural Resource Management, Research &
    Evaluation<br/>
    Email: newaz_bard@yahoo.com, newazctg@gmail.com<br/></p>

<p><img src="file:///android_asset/abdullah.jpg" width="150px;" height="180px;"><br/>
    <b>Joint Director (Health & Nutrition) </b><br/>
    Abdullah Al Mamun<br/>
    M.P.S. (Food and Nutrition Planning), UPLB, Philippines<br/>
    M.Sc. in Nutrition and B.Sc.(Hons.) in Biochemistry, Dhaka University<br/>
    Post Graduate Diploma in Food and Nutrition Security, Wageningen University, The
    Netherlands<br/>
    Certificate Course (GIS and ICT Application for Rural Development), NIRD, Hyderabad, India<br/>
    Field of Specialization: Nutrition and ICT<br/>
    Emil: mamun_bard@hotmail.com, mamunbard@gmail.com<br/></p>

<p><img src="file:///android_asset/ranjankumar.jpg" width="150px;" height="180px;"><br/>
    <b>Joint Director (Project)</b><br/>
    Ranjan Kumar Guha<br/>
    M.Com. (Management), Dhaka University<br/>
    B.Com. (Hons.)<br/>
    Filed of Specialization: Development Management, Poverty Monitoring at Local Level<br/>
    Email: rkguha@live.com<br/></p>

<p><img src="file:///android_asset/nasimaakther.jpg" width="150px;" height="180px;"><br/>
    <b>Joint Director (Rural Sociology & Demography)</b><br/>
    Nasima Akhter<br/>
    M.Ed., Dhaka University<br/>
    M.S.S. (Sociology), Dhaka University<br/>
    B.S.S. (Hons.), Sociology, Dhaka University<br/>
    Certificate Course on Food & Nutrition Program Planning and Management, Philippines and Sri
    Lanka<br/>
    International ToT Course on Women\'s Income Generating Activities, NIRD, India<br/>
    Regional Workshop on Women in Politics, Bombay, India<br/>
    Livelihood Development for Rural Women and Poverty Reduction, NIRD, India<br/>
    Field of Specialization: Education Development and Gender Development, Project
    Experimentation and Management<br/>
    Email: nasimanarsingdi@yahoo.com<br/></p>

<p><img src="file:///android_asset/shisir.jpg" width="150px;" height="180px;"><br/>
    <b>Joint Director (Training)</b><br/>
    Dr. Shishir Kumar Munshi<br/>
    Ph.D., Bangladesh Agricultural University, Mymensingh<br/>
    M.Sc. (Horticulture), Bangladesh Agricultural University, Mymensingh<br/>
    B.Sc.Agriculture(Hons.), BAU, Mymensingh<br/>
    Certificate Course (Innovative Approaches to Sustainable Farming), The Wagenineen UR, The
    Netherlands<br/>
    Certificate Course (Vegetable Production), EICA, Egypt<br/>
    Field of Specialization: Horticulture and Bio-Resource Management<br/>
    Email:munshishishir@yahoo.com<br/></p>


<p><img src="file:///android_asset/msirin.jpg" width="150px;" height="180px;"><br/>
    <b>Joint Director (Rural Sociology)</b><br/>
    Irin Parvin<br/>
    M.A. in (Library and Information Science), University of Dhaka<br/>
    B.A.(Hons.)<br/>
    Diploma in Computer Hardware and Trouble Shooting, DIIT, Comilla<br/>
    International Training Course in Information Communication Technology in Rural Development,
    NIRD, India<br/>
    Field of Specialization: Information Management and ICT<br/>
    Email: irin_bard@yahoo.com, irin.parvin@gmail.com<br/>
</p>
</body>
</html>
        ]]></string>


</resources>
